<string name="about_text">
    <![CDATA[  
        <p><big>
            <font color="#007bb5"><b>About</b></font>
        </big></p>
        
        <p>Escorting is an official process in which a child is taken away from an environment that is dangerous. This process
            is enacted by Oranga Tamariki, or the Ministry for Children, as it is better known—the government agency for issues
            surrounding the welfare of children.</p>
        
        <p><big>
            <font color="#007bb5"><b>Types of Escorting</b></font>
        </big></p>
        
        <p>
            <font color="#cc6633"><b>Planned Escorts:</b></font> Planned removals are those that are pre-arranged, where Oranga
            Tamariki work with the families and other agencies about the strategy for a child\'s relocation. The process involves
            thorough assessments and planning that need to be carried out to ensure the safety and well-being of the child.
        </p>
        <p>
            <font color="#cc6633"><b>Urgent Uplifting:</b></font> Urgent removals are those in which the child is at imminent
            risk, and something needs to be done straight away to ensure their safety. It may be that a child is considered at
            immediate risk of harm, and Oranga Tamariki may not have to notify the family but go straight into taking action to
            keep the child safe.
        </p>
        
        <p><big>
            <font color="#007bb5"><b>Who takes custody of the child after removal?</b></font>
        </big></p>
        
        <p>
            The child that is taken away from
            home falls into the custody of Oranga Tamariki Ministry for Children. This child will be sent to stay with a family
            member or somebody that he or she knows well. In case this may not be practicable or appropriate, the child could be
            placed into a ministry home or residence.
        </p>
        <p>
            Unless there is a good reason against it, you should be told as soon as possible about what is happening and why, and
            about what is likely to happen in the future. You may also telephone the Ministry at any time of day or night for
            information.
        </p>
        <p>
            When a child is taken away from home and put into care by Oranga Tamariki Ministry for Children, it must be brought
            before a Family Court within five days. You will be advised of the court decision.
        </p>
        
        <p><a href="https://www.howtolaw.co/know-your-rights-when-a-child-is-removed-from-your-care-392254">know your rights
            when a child is removed from your care in NZ</a></p>
    ]]>
</string>

<string name="escorting_text">
    <![CDATA[
        <p><big>
            <font color="#007bb5"><b>Process of Escorting</b></font>
        </big></p>
        
        <p>
            <font color="#cc6633"><b>Risk Assessment:</b></font>
        </p>
        
        <p>
            A very careful risk assessment is carried out to review the
            environment and decide whether there is a requirement for escorting the child for safety purposes.
        </p>
        <p> Oranga Tamariki loses custody when any other person or agency takes legal custody of the child.</p>
        
        
        <p>
            <font color="#cc6633"><b>Authority to Escort and Escorting Conditions:</b></font>
        </p>
        
        <p>
            Escort is granted by a manager at
            Oranga Tamariki, and conditions include the fact that:
        </p>
        
        <ul>
            <li> There should be a minimum of two escort staff who have had.</li>
            <li> An escort of the same gender as the child whenever possible.</li>
            <li> The staff have to be well trained to handle de-escalation.</li>
        </ul>
        
        <p><big>
            <font color="#007bb5"><b>Risk assessment and planning of the journey</b></font>
        </big></p>
        
        <p>
            <font color="#cc6633"><b>Informed Escort Strategy:</b></font>
        </p>
        
        <p>
            This is a strategy that involves a lot of planning and
            communication, with information provided to all parties, including the child, the family, and caregivers, so that
            all are aware of the reason for and the procedure for the escort.
        </p>
        <p> Refer to Oranga Tamariki\'s escorting policy for further information on these processes.</p>
        
        <p><big>
                <font color="#007bb5"><b>Legal Rights of Caregivers/Parents</b></font>
            </big></p>
        <p>
            <font color="#cc6633"><b>Legal Parent Rights:</b></font> Parents have some legal rights in the process of escorting,
            such as:
        </p>
        <ul>
            <li>Being informed in advance of plans for escorting their child;</li>
            <li>A chance to comment and express views about what occurs during the escorting process.</li>
            <li>Access to Information: Being informed of the reasons for escorting and where the child is being taken.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>For more details on these, refer to Community Law\'s guidebook to dealing with Oranga Tamariki.</p>
        
        <p><a href="https://communitylaw.org.nz/community-law-manual/test/family-matters/oranga-tamariki/">Community Law\'s</a>
        </p>
    ]]>
</string>

<string name="caregivers_text">
    <![CDATA[
        <p><big>
            <font color="#007bb5"><b>Legal Rights of Caregivers and Parents</b></font>
        </big></p>
        
        <p><big>
            <font color="#007bb5"><b>What are the rights of parents when it comes to this matter during eviction.</b></font>
        </big></p>
        
        <ul>
            <li>
                <font color="#cc6633"><b>Right to Information: </b></font>
                A parent can be informed of the decisions made about the child, including any plan for
                escorting. Oranga Tamariki shall inform a parent of the grounds of escort, destination, and such other relevant
                information.
            </li>
            <li>
                <font color="#cc6633"><b>Participation in Decision-Making: </b></font>
                Parents are entitled to take part in decision-making on matters relating to
                their child\'s care and protection. This includes the opportunity to take part in Family Group Conferences and
                other meetings which may be held in order to formulate a plan, which may then involve escorting.
            </li>
            <li>
                <font color="#cc6633"><b>Access to Advocacy: </b></font>
                Parents should have access to independent advocacy that might assist them in dealing with
                Oranga Tamariki. An advocate may assist parents in negotiating their rights and processes so their voice is
                firmly heard.
            </li>
            <li>
                <font color="#cc6633"><b>Right to Legal Representation: </b></font>
                If legal proceedings are initiated, such as the application for a Care or
                Protection Order, parents have rights to legal representation. Agencies like Community Law provide free legal
                advice and representation if the criteria for eligibility are met.
            </li>
            <li>
                <font color="#cc6633"><b>Right to Complain: </b></font>
                Parents have a right to comment on the process of escorting or any actions taken by Oranga
                Tamariki. Oranga Tamariki takes avenues of responding to feedback and complaints addressing such concerns.
            </li>
            <li>
                <font color="#cc6633"><b>Consideration of Cultural Connections: </b></font>
                Oranga Tamariki shall, in respect of considerations for Māori families,
                take into account the whanau, hapū, and iwi of the child when it engages in decision-making processes. In this
                respect, this shall guarantee that all cultural identity and relationship matters are preserved as the child
                is escorted.
            </li>
            <li>
                <font color="#cc6633"><b>Right to Privacy: </b></font>
                Parents have the right to privacy in relation to personal information. Oranga Tamariki has the
                obligation to ensure that all information is kept confidential, only disseminated when necessary and
                appropriate.
            </li>
            <li>
                <font color="#cc6633"><b>Right to Support Services: </b></font>
                Parents may be provided support services that can help resolve whatever issues brought or
                Oranga Tamariki into their lives in the first instance. It may include counselling, parenting programs, and
                other
                resources that have a focus on family reunification and well-being.
            </li>
        </ul>
        
        <p>
            It would be expected that parents engage positively with Oranga Tamariki, ask questions if they don\'t understand,
            and utilise support services in a constructive way that recognizes what is in the best interest of their children.
        </p>
        
        <p>
            During the process of taking a child away, Oranga Tamariki allows the parents a few core rights. Parents have the
            right to be fully informed regarding decisions surrounding their child, such as why their relocation is necessary
            and where that would take place. Parents can also be given the chance to join decision-making activities like the
            Family Group Conferences and be able to contribute to plans drafted for the care of the child. Individual advocacy
            supports parents to ensure their perspective is recognized. Representation can be obtained legally about any formal
            proceedings. Some services are free for those meeting eligibility criteria. Parents also have the right to make
            complaints about the removal process, and Oranga Tamariki is committed to responding to these concerns. With Māori
            families, the continuation of cultural links is held in high regard; this offers assurance that the child\'s identity
            and the family connection remain intact. Personal information is kept confidential while services provided for
            parents may include counselling and parenting programs with regards to maintaining and reunifying a family. Parents
            should be made to feel welcome to play an active role in being constructive, asking questions and seeking resources
            on behalf of their children.
        </p>
        
        <p><a href="https://www.justice.govt.nz/family/care-of-children/guardianship/being-a-guardian/">Care of Children</a></p>
    ]]>
</string>

<string name="custodians_text">
    <![CDATA[
        <p><big>
            <font color="#007bb5"><b>For Custodians</b></font>
        </big></p>
        
        <p>
            <font color="#cc6633"><b>What is the eligibility criteria?</b></font>
        </p>
        
        <p>
            To be appointed as a custodian for a child in
            New Zealand, non-parents must apply to the Family Court, providing detailed information about their relationship
            with the child and their suitability for guardianship. If the child\'s current guardians consent to the appointment,
            the process may be more straightforward. In the absence of such consent, the court evaluates the application based
            on the child\'s best interests, considering factors such as the applicant\'s relationship to the child, the child\'s
            safety and well-being, the preservation of the child\'s cultural heritage, and the child\'s own preferences if they
            are mature enough to express them.
        </p>
        <p>It\'s advisable to seek legal counsel during this process; organisations like Community Law offer free legal advice
            and assistance.</p>
        
        <p><big>
            <font color="#007bb5"><b>Criteria for Appointment as Custodian</b></font>
        </big></p>
        
        <p>
            <font color="#cc6633"><b>Application to the Family Court:</b></font> Non-parents must make an application to the
            Family Court for being appointed as a custodian.
        </p>
        <p> The application ought to involve filing appropriate forms and details about your relationship with the child, how
            befitting you are to become the guardian of the child.</p>
        <p>
            <font color="#cc6633"><b>Consent:</b></font> If the child\'s parents are the current guardians and they are in
            approval of your appointment, then it may be easier. Where parental consent is absent, the court will determine
            based on the best interest of the child.
        </p>
        <p>
            <font color="#cc6633"><b>Factors Court Consider:</b></font>
        </p>
        
        <ul>
            <li> Best Interest: Here, the court looks at the security and safety of the child.</li>
            <li> Relationship to Existing Parents/Guardians: The court examines your relation to the child, whether a parent,
                sibling, or family friend, to whom the care of a child was initially provided.</li>
            <li> Cultural Heritage: The court wants to preserve the child\'s cultural heritage.</li>
            <li> Child\'s Preference: The court may consider the child\'s view on this matter if he/she is old and mature enough to
                give his/her preference.</li>
        </ul>
        
        <p>
            <font color="#cc6633"><b>Legal Advice:</b></font> It is advisable to seek legal advice in the case you want to
            pursue this route of custodianship.
        </p>
        
        <p>
            It is advisable to seek legal advice in the course of an application. The agencies like <a
            href="https://communitylaw.org.nz/resources/">Community Law</a> offer free legal advice and assistance.</p>
        
        <p>
            To be appointed as a custodian for a child in New Zealand, non-parents must apply to the Family Court, providing
            detailed information about their relationship with the child and their suitability for guardianship. If the child\'s
            current guardians consent to the appointment, the process may be more straightforward. In the absence of such
            consent, the court evaluates the application based on the child\'s best interests, considering factors such as the
            applicant\'s relationship to the child, the child\'s safety and well-being, the preservation of the child\'s cultural
            heritage, and the child\'s own preferences if they are mature enough to express them. It\'s advisable to seek legal
            counsel during this process; organisations like <a href="https://communitylaw.org.nz/resources/">Community Law</a>
            offer free legal advice and assistance.
        </p>
        
        <p><a href="https://www.edenfamilylaw.co.nz/topics/care-of-children/child-custody-who-can-apply-to-the-family-court-for-a-parenting-order">
        Eden Family Law. (n.d.). Child custody: Who can apply to the family court for a parenting order?.</a></p>
        
        <p><a href="https://www.orangatamariki.govt.nz">Oranga Tamariki. (n.d.). Guidelines on child removal processes. Oranga
                Tamariki - Ministry for Children.</a></p>
    ]]>
</string>