<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools" tools:ignore="MissingTranslation,TypographyEllipsis">

    <!-- TODO set home text -->
    <string name="app_name">Information</string>
    <string name="home_title">AWAI</string>
    <string name="home_description">your trusted support for Tamariki and Rangatahi</string>
    <string name="language">English</string>
    <string name="test_long">This is a long test text…This is a long test text…This is a long test text…
        This is a long test text…This is a long test text…</string>

    <!-- TODO: set PARAGRAPH text in four layouts -->
    <string name="information_paragraph">Content for Information</string>
    <string name="escorting_paragraph">
        <![CDATA[
            <p><big><font color="#007bb5"><b>What is Escorting?</b></font></big></p>

            <p><font>Escorting is an official process in which a child is taken away from an environment that is dangerous. This process is enacted by Oranga Tamariki, or the Ministry for Children, as it is better known—the government agency of issues surrounding the welfare of children.</font></p>

            <p><big><font color="#007bb5"><b>Types of Escorting</b></font></big></p>

            <p><font><b>Care and Protection Escorts:</b> Relocation for children who require such due to safety and care concerns.</font></p>

            <p><font><b>Youth Justice Escorts:</b> Young people who come into contact with youth justice, either by appearing in a court or being taken to a residence, are escorted.</font></p>

            <p><big><font color="#007bb5"><b>Process of Escorting</b></font></big></p>

            <p><small><font color="#cc6633"><b>Risk Assessment:</b></font></small></p>

            <p><font>A very careful risk assessment is carried out to review the environment and decide whether there is a requirement for escorting the child for safety purposes.</font></p>

            <p><font>Oranga Tamariki loses custody when any other person or agency takes legal custody of the child.</font></p>

            <p><small><font color="#cc6633"><b>Authority to Escort and Escorting Conditions:</b></font></small></p>

            <p><font>Escort is granted by a manager at Oranga Tamariki, and conditions include the fact that:</font></p>

            <p><font>There should be a minimum of two escort staff who have had.</font></p>

            <p><font>An escort of the same gender as the child whenever possible.</font></p>

            <p><font>The staff have to be well trained to handle de-escalation.</font></p>

            <p><small><font color="#cc6633"><b>Risk assessment and planning of the journey</b></font></small></p>

            <p><font>Informed Escort Strategy: This is a strategy that involves a lot of planning and communication, with information provided to all parties, including the child, the family, and caregivers, so that all are aware of the reason for and the procedure for the escort.</font></p>

            <p><font>Refer to Oranga Tamarikis escorting policy for further information on these processes.</font></p>

            <p><font>Legal Parent Rights: <a href="https://communitylaw.org.nz/community-law-manual/test/family-matters/oranga-tamariki/">Oranga Tamariki - Community Law</a></font></p>

            <p><font>Parents have some legal rights in the process of escorting, such as:</font></p>

            <p><font>Being informed in advance of plans for escorting their child;</font></p>

            <p><font>A chance to comment and express views about what occurs during the escorting process.</font></p>

            <p><font>Access to Information: Being informed of the reasons for escorting and where the child is being taken.</font></p>

            <p><font>For more details on these, refer to Community Laws guidebook to dealing with Oranga Tamariki.</font></p>

            <p><big><font color="#007bb5"><b>Legal Rights of Caregivers</b></font></big></p>

            <p><font>Caregivers also have some rights, including:</font></p>

            <p><small><font color="#cc6633"><b>Notified decisions:</b></font></small></p>

            <p><font>Being informed regarding any escorting arrangement that involves the child in their care.</font></p>

            <p><font>Support: Receiving the necessary assistance and support in order for the child to prepare themselves with the escort.</font></p>

            <p><font>Participation: An opportunity to have their views heard and to raise concerns about their child.</font></p>

            <p><font>For more detailed information on caregiver s rights, refer to the policies of Oranga Tamariki on the processes they follow for allegations of harm in care/custody situations: </font></p>

            <p><a href="https://www.howtolaw.co/know-your-rights-when-a-child-is-removed-from-your-care-392254">know your rights when a child is removed from your care</a></p>

            <p><big><font color="#007bb5"><b>Who takes custody of the child after removal?</b></font></big></p>

            <p><font>The child that is taken away from home falls into the custody of Oranga Tamariki - Ministry for Children. This child will be sent to stay with a family member or somebody that he or she knows well. In case this may not be practicable or appropriate, the child could be placed into a ministry home or residence.</font></p>

            <p><font>Unless there is a good reason against it, you should be told as soon as possible about what is happening and why, and about what is likely to happen in the future. You may also telephone the Ministry at any time of day or night for information.</font></p>

            <p><font>When a child is taken away from home and put into care by Oranga Tamariki - Ministry for Children, it must be brought before a Family Court within five days. You will be advised of the court decision.</font></p>

            <p><a href="https://www.howtolaw.co/know-your-rights-when-a-child-is-removed-from-your-care-392254">know your rights when a child is removed from your care</a></p>
        ]]>
    </string>

    <string name="custodians_paragraph">Content for Custodians</string>
    <string name="caregivers_paragraph">Content for Caregivers</string>

    <!--  TODO: set buttons text -->
    <string name="button_change_language">English</string>
    <string name="button_information">About</string>
    <string name="button_escorting">Process Of Escorting</string>
    <string name="button_custodians">Legal Right of Custodians</string>
    <string name="button_caregivers">Legal Right Of Caregivers</string>
    <string name="button_yes">YES</string>
    <string name="button_no">NO</string>
    <string name="button_next">NEXT QUESTION</string>
    <string name="button_start_quiz">Test Your Knowledge</string>
    <string name="button_retry">RETRY</string>
    <string name="button_complete">COMPLETE</string>

    <!-- TODO: set questions text -->
    <string name="your_answer">Your Answer: %1$s</string>
    <string name="correct_answer">Correct Answer: %1$s</string>
    <string name="question_text">%1$d.%2$s</string>
    <string name="question_idx_in_total">Question %1$d in %2$d</string>
    <string name="question_1_text">Is escorting only applicable to children who have been involved in criminal activity?</string>
    <string name="question_2_text">Is it mandatory for an escort to always be of the same gender as the child?</string>
    <string name="question_3_text">Are parents legally allowed to comment on the escorting process of their child?</string>
    <string name="question_4_text">Can a child be placed in a ministry residence if staying with a family member is not feasible?</string>
    <string name="question_5_text">Is Oranga Tamariki required to bring a child before a Family Court within five days after taking custody?</string>
    <string name="question_1_explanation">Escorting is not limited to children involved in criminal activities. It includes Care and Protection Escorts (children needing relocation due to safety concerns) as well as Youth Justice Escorts (children involved with youth justice). So, it applies to both children in need of protection and those involved with the justice system.</string>
    <string name="question_2_explanation">While it is preferred for the escort to be of the same gender as the child, it is not a strict requirement. The guidelines specify it \"whenever possible,\" meaning it is flexible depending on the situation.</string>
    <string name="question_3_explanation">Parents have the right to comment and express views about the escorting process. This is part of their legal rights during the escorting process.</string>
    <string name="question_4_explanation">If the child cannot be placed with a family member or someone they know well, they may be placed in a ministry home or residence as a temporary measure.</string>
    <string name="question_5_explanation">Once Oranga Tamariki takes custody of a child, the child must be brought before a Family Court within five days. The parent or caregiver will be informed about the court\'s decision.</string>
</resources>